Guide to the Picture File, 1700s-1980s and undated RL.01025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- People Series, 1700s-1970s; 1
  - Hooper, William, 1870, engraving (Box 53)
  - Hoover, (Henry) Lou, 1928 Aug. 19, 1 clipping and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 24, Folder M1083)
  - Hoover, Lou Henry, late 1920s?, black-and-white photograph (Box 58, Folder M1797)
    Harris and Ewing, Washington D.C. studio stamp; card mount inscribed "To my dear Saint, Ada de Mitchell," and signed by Lou Hoover.
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 24, Folder M1084)
  - Hope, Leslie Town (Bob), 1949, black-and-white photograph (Box 42)
    Includes dedication and signature of Bob Hope.
  - Horne, George, undated, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1085)
  - Horton, F. C., 1919 Mar. 15, postcard (Box 24, Folder M1086)
  - Houdini, Harry, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 24, Folder M1087)
    Transferred from the Parapsychology Laboratory Papers.
  - Houston, George Smith, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 24, Folder M1088)
  - Howard, Charles, Second Baron Howard of Effingham, First Earl of Nottingham, undated, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1089)
  - Howard, Henry, Earl of Surrey (circa 1517-1547), 1834 Oct. 1, engraving (Box 53)
  - Howard, Oliver O., 1800s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 24, Folder M1090)
  - Howard, Thomas III, Fourth Duke of Norfolk of the Howard house, 1833 June 1, engraving (Box 54)
  - Howard, Thomas III, Fourth Duke of Norfolk of the Howard house, undated and 1833 June 1, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1092)
  - Howard, Thomas, First Earl of Suffolk and First Baron Howard de Walden, 1806 May 20, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1091)
  - Howe, Albion Parris, 1800s, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1093)
  - Howe, Robert, 1895 July, engraving (Box 24, Folder M1094)
  - Howley, William, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1829 and 1830, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1095)
  - Howley, William, Bishop of London, 1886, engraving (Box 42)
  - Hoxie, Walter John, 1934 Apr. 12 and 1900s, 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1096)
  - Huckleberry Finn's Home (Box 19, Folder M717)
  - Hugar, Isaac, undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 25, Folder M1097)
    Illustration is a copy of an original sketch. Transferred from the Marmaduke Floyd collection.
  - Hugo, Victor, 1877, lithograph (Box 25, Folder M1098)
  - Hume, Joseph, undated, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1099)
  - Hunter, David, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Hurst, Robert Withers, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1100)
    Includes faint signature on reverse side.
  - Huskisson, William, 1840, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1101)
  - Indians Hunting the Bison, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1103)
  - Ingram, Arthur Foley Winnington, undated, postcard (Box 25, Folder M1106)
  - Iredell, James (1751-1799), 1889, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1107)
  - Irving, Edward, 1823 Aug. 21, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1108)
  - Irving, Sir Henry, undated, 3 postcards (Box 25, Folder M1109)
  - Irving, Washington, 1800s and 1921, 1 black-and-white photograph and 1 engraving (Box 25, Folder M1110)
    Photograph is a copy of a painting.
  - Itinerant peddler with a can in one hand and case in the other, posed studio photograph, 1880s?, carte-des-visites photograph (Box 58, Folder M1804)
    Photographer stamped on mount, front and back: Dana, corner 14th St. and 6th Ave., New York. There are handwritten lines of sales pointers or editorial instructions on back, including the phrase "Ruggle's canned goods," and "Ruggles Meat Pork in can."
  - Izard, Mrs. Ralph (Alice Delancey), undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1111)
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1113)
    The images are copies of J. W. Dodge's portrait of Jackson.
  - Jackson, Andrew, 1845, 1861, 1877, and 1800s, 4 engravings and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1112)
    Photograph is a copy of a portrait.
  - Jackson, Andrew, his slave, "Uncle Alfred," 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1114)
  - Jackson, Henry Rootes, undated, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1115)
  - Jackson, James, undated, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1117)
  - Jackson, Mary Anna (Morrison), (Mrs. Thomas Jonathan Jackson), undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1118)
  - Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographs and 5 card photographs (Box 25, Folder M1120)
  - Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Jackson, Thomas Jonathan, 1866 and 1800s, 6 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1120)
  - Jackson, Thomas, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1119)
  - Jackson, William Hicks, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1122)
  - Jackson, William, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1121)
  - Jacobs, W. R., undated, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1123)
  - Jahnz, Emil H., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1124)
  - James II, King of Great Britain, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1125)
  - James II, King of Great Britain, undated, 2 engravings (Box 54)
  - James, Henry, 1967 Oct. 30, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1126)
    Published first on Oct. 30, 1967 in his The American Scene (Horizon Press).
  - James, William, 1907, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 2)
    Negative included.
  - Jarvis, Thomas Jordan, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1127)
  - Jay, William, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1128)
  - Jefferson, Joseph (as Rip Van Winkle), undated, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1129)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1805, 1862, 1868 and 1800s, 7 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1130)
  - Jellicoe, John Rushworth, First Earl Jellicoe, 1914, postcard (Box 25, Folder M1131)
  - Jervis, John, Earl of St. Vincent, 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1132)
  - Joffre, Joseph Jacques Cesaire (general in WWI), undated, postcard (Box 25, Folder M1133)
  - John III or Sobieski, King of Poland (1674-1696), undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1134)
  - Johns, John, undated, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1135)
  - Johnson, Andrew, 1864, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1136)
  - Johnson, Andrew, 1865, 1907, 2 card photographs (Box 25, Folder M1137)
  - Johnson, Andrew, 1907, 2 lithographs (Box 54)
    Two copies.
  - Johnson, Andrew, undated, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 44)
  - Johnson, Bradley Tyler, undated, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1138)
  - Johnson, Claudia Alta "Ladybird" (Taylor), 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1139)
  - Johnson, D. C. (?), 1800s, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1140)
  - Johnson, Herschel V., 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1141)
  - Johnson, Jack, 1908, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 2)
    Poster, "Champion of the World."
  - Johnson, John A., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1142)
  - Johnson, Joseph E., 19th c. (Johnston, Joseph E.), black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 29)
  - Johnson, Lemuel (?), 1800s, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1143)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines and family, 1964, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1145)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1144)
  - Johnson, Reverdy, undated, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1146)
    Photograph is of a bust.
  - Johnson, Richard Menton, 1800s, lithograph (Box 42)
  - Johnson, Samuel, undated, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1147)
    One engraving is a copy of a full length portrait.
  - Johnson, Thomas, 1890, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1148)
  - Johnson, William Samuel (1727-1819), 1888, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1150)
  - Johnson, William, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1149)
  - Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographs and 1 engraving (Box 25, Folder M1151)
    Both photographs are from the scrapbook of Chas E. Jones. One photograph is of a bust.
  - Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Johnston, Joseph E., 1800s, lithograph (Box 42)
    From "The Confederate Soldier in the Civil War."
  - Johnston, Joseph E., 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Johnston, Joseph E., 1866 and 1800s, 2 card photographs and 3 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1152)
    Includes signature. Negative available.
  - Jokai, Maurus, 1896 and 1899, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1153)
  - Jones, Charles C., Jr., 1800s, 2 engravings and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1154)
  - Jones, Charles Edgeworth, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1155)
    From the Chas E. Jones scrapbook. Negative available.
  - Jones, David R., 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Jones, John Paul (1747-1792), 1920, color lithograph (Box 61)
    Large lithograph of sketch in russet pastel (?) by Albert Rosenthal, after a terracotta sculpture.
  - Jones, John Paul (1747-1792), 19th century?, black-and-white engraving (Box 25, Folder M1156)
  - Jones, Noble Wymberly, undated, 2 engravings (Box 25, Folder M1156)
  - Jones, Sir William, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1157)
  - Jones, William, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1158)
  - Jordan, Archibald Currie, undated, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1159)
    This folder also contains pictures of the Jordan home as well as the Jordan family store.
  - Jordan, Samuel Hagris and family, 1881 and 1800s, 7 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1160)
    Family members in each picture are identified on the back.
  - Joyner, James Yadkin, 1909 Sept., black-and-white illustration (Box 25, Folder M1161)
  - Kean, Edmund, Esq., in the dress presented to and worn by him on the occasion of his being chosen a Chief and Prince of the Huron TribeŬ 1827, black-and-white engraving (Box 59)
  - Kell, John McIntosh, 1800s, clipping (Box 25, Folder M1162)
  - Kemp, The Rt. Rev. James, undated, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1163)
  - Kenan, William Rand, Jr., 1800s, card photograph (Box 25, Folder M1164)
  - Kendal and Dent's Chronological chart of the Kings and Queens of England, 807-1901, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Kendrick, Peter Richard, 1891 Nov. 29, color illustration (Box 25, Folder M1165)
    Illustration is a colored engraving.
  - Kenley, John M., 1890, engraving (Box 25, Folder M1166)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald and Lyndon Baines Johnson, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1169)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, 1960 and undated, 2 postcards and 4 black-and-white photographs (Box 25, Folder M1168)
    Two photographs include a signature.
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, et al., undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 25, Folder M1167)
    Includes signatures of J. F. Kennedy and Jacqueline Kennedy.
  - Kennedy, John Pendleton, 1850, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1170)
  - Kennedy, Robert Francis, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1171)
  - Kenton, Simon, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1172)
  - Keppel, Augustus, First Viscount Keppel, 1834 July 1, 2 engravings (Box 54)
  - Ketcham, E. H., undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1173)
  - Keyes, Erasmus Darwin, 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1174)
  - King, Alice Marguerite, undated, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1175)
    Includes biographical information on back.
  - King, Rufus, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1176)
  - King, Wiliam Lyon Mackenzie, 1929 Mar., black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1177)
  - Kitchener, Horatio Herbert Kitchener, 1st Earl Kitchener, 1900s, postcard (Box 26, Folder M1178)
  - Knight, Frances Zerwiah (Beall), 1800s, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1179)
  - Knight, John, 1864 and 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 black-and-white illustration (Box 26, Folder M1180)
    Illustration is a copy of a painting.
  - Knox, John, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1181)
  - Kohn, August, 1900s, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1182)
    From the William Ramsey, James Calvin, and Robert Reid Hemphill Mss.
  - Kollock, Edward Campbell, 1800s, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 26, Folder M1183)
  - Kollock, George Jones, 1800s, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 26, Folder M1184)
  - Kollock, Lemuel, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1185)
  - Kollock, P. M., 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 26, Folder M1186)
  - Kor, Karl Theodor, portrait and autograph manuscript texts, 1800s, engraving; manuscripts (Box 45)
    Also contains correspondence as well as a short handwritten poem, signed by K(?)r.
  - Kotzenstein, Charles J. (?), 1931 Dec. 19, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1187)
    Includes a correspondence signed by Kotzenstein.
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1921 and 1800s, 1 black-and-white photographic illustration, 1 black-and-white illustration and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1188)
    Pictures concerning the Klan show full uniform and the S. Spofford home in Pulaski, TN, where the first Klan was organized.
  - Kyper, Kay, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1189)
  - La Pouse, de, Jean Francois de Galaup, Count, undated, 2 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1190)
  - Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, Marquis de, 1833, 1852 and 1800s, 3 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1191)
  - Lamar, L. Q. C., 1875, 1889 and 1800s, 2 engravings and 3 card photographs (Box 26, Folder M1192)
  - Lamb, William, Second Viscount Melbourne, 1832, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1193)
  - Lambeth, John Walter, 1900s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Lang, Anton, undated, 4 postcards (Box 26, Folder M1194)
    Two postcards contain pencil signatures of Lang.
  - Langston, John Dallas, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1195)
  - Large group of unidentified people in fancy dress, circa 1920s, black-and-white photograph (Box 58, Folder M1806)
    Transferred from Lou Hanks papers. Group is probably affiliated with a music event or organization. In paper portfolio.
  - Larner, Robert Martin, 1895 July 15, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1196)
  - Lassiter, Charles T., undated, postcard (Box 26, Folder M1197)
  - Latrobe, Osman, 1866 July, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1198)
  - Laud, William (1573-1645), undated, engraving (Box 54)
  - Laughinghouse, Charles O'H., 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1199)
  - Laurens, Henry, 1814, 1862 and 1800s, 4 engravings and 1 black-and-white illustration (Box 26, Folder M1200)
  - Laurens, John, undated, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1201)
    Photograph is of a miniature. Transferred from the Richard L. Maury Mss. Includes a possible signature.
  - Law, Evander McIvor, circa 1860s, 2 clippings (Box 26, Folder M1202)
    Both images are from the scrapbook of Charles E. Jones.
  - Lawrence, Sir Thomas (1769-1830), undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1203)
  - Lawton, A. R. and Sarah (Alexander), 1888 and 1800s, 1 engraving and 1 card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1204)
    The card photograph of Sarah Lawton contains additional information on the back.
  - Lee and His Generals, 1907, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Lee at the grave of Stonewall Jackson, 1862, black-and-white engraving (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Lee Family Pictures (Robert E. Lee), 1831-1875 and 1800s, 4 black-and-white photographs, 1 black-and-white photographic illustration 3 card photographs (Box 26, Folder M1218.1)
    Two of the black-and-white photographs are copies of paintings.
  - Lee Family Pictures (Robert E. Lee), 1868, 1870 and 1800s, 3 card photographs and 1 black-and-white illustration (Box 26, Folder M1218.2)
    The illustration is a copy of a painting.
  - Lee, Charles, 1852 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1205)
  - Lee, F. W., 1898 Dec. 25, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1206)
    Includes autographed note on reverse of photograph.
  - Lee, Fitzhugh, 1800s, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1207)
    Photograph includes signature.
  - Lee, Fitzhugh, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
    Removed from folder M1207.
  - Lee, George Washington Custis, 1800s, 3 clippings and 1 card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1208)
    The clippings appear on the same page from Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Lee, Henry, 1862 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1209)
  - Lee, Richard Henry, 1861 and 1800s, 2 engravings (Box 26, Folder M1210)
  - Lee, Robert E. 1800s, engraving (Box 42)
  - Lee, Robert E. and Thomas Jonathan Jackson, circa 1860s, black-and-white illustration (Box 26, Folder M1212)
    Illustration is a card photograph of a painting.
  - Lee, Robert E., 1800s, 1 black-and-white poster, 1 engraving (Box 54)
    Poster with "Compliments of Cotton Route"; contains Lee's farewell speech to his troops as well as his standing portrait.
  - Lee, Robert E., circa 1860s, engraving and black-and-white illustration (Box 26, Folder M1211)
  - Lee, Robert Edward, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Lee, Robert Edward, 1835, 1866, 1903 Nov. 10 and 1800s, 2 card photographs, 5 black-and-white illustrations, and 1 clipping (Box 26, Folder M1213.2)
    The illustrations include copies of black-and-white photographs, an engraving and a painting. Clipping appears on a page of Charles E. Jones' scrapbook.
  - Lee, Robert Edward, 1865 and 1800s, 2 black-and-white photographs and 1 card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1213.3)
    Two photographs are copies and the card photograph is enclosed by a blue ribbon.
  - Lee, Robert Edward, 1865 Apr. 21, black-and-white photograph (Box 26, Folder M1214)
    The original of this photograph is reported to have been made soon after the Civil War.
  - Lee, Robert Edward, 1866 and 1800s, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1213.1)
  - Lee, Robert Edward, undated, silhouette (Box 26, Folder M1215)
  - Lee, Stephen Dill, 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 postcard (Box 26, Folder M1216)
    The photograph appears on a page of Charles E. Jones' scrapbook and comes signed by S. D. Lee.
  - Lee, William Henry Fitzhugh, 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 clipping (Box 26, Folder M1217)
  - Leidy, Joseph, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1219)
  - Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1800s, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1220)
  - Leland, John, undated, 2 black-and-white illustrations (Box 26, Folder M1221)
    Both photographs are of the same painting.
  - Lenbach, Franz Von, undated, postcard (Box 26, Folder M1222)
  - Leo XII, Pope, 1760-1829, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1223)
  - Leonideas, 1807 Sept. 19, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1224)
  - Leopold I, King of the Belgians and Charlotte Augusta, Princess of Great Britain, 1818 Mar., engraving (Box 26, Folder M1226)
    This engraving is entitled: First interview of the Princess Charlotte with Prince Leopold.
  - Leopold I, King of the Belgians, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
    Engraving is a copy of a pencil sketch.
  - Leopold I, King of the Belgians, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1225)
    Engraving is entitled, Marriage of the Princess Charlotte of Wales, to Prince Leopold of Saxe-Cobourg.
  - Leopold II, King of Belgium and his wife Henrietta, Maria of Austria, who became Queen of Belgium, undated, 2 card photographs (Box 26, Folder M1227)
  - Leslie (Lesley), David, First Baron of Newark, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1228)
  - Leslie, Sir John (1766-1832), 1833, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1229)
  - Letcher, John, 1877, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1230)
    Transferred from the Branch-Cunningham Collection pictures.
  - Levert, Francis I., 1869 May 5, card photograph (Box 26, Folder M1231)
    Includes dated signature.
  - Leveson-Gower, Granville George, Second Earl Granville, undated, engraving (Box 26, Folder M1232)
    Engraved by W. Roffe from a photograph by Elliott & Fry.
  - Levy(?) et Neurdein Postcards, undated, 86 postcards (Box 26, Folder M1233)
    From a set of 86 postcards featuring French nobility and royalty.
  - Lewis, Mrs. Lawrence (Eleanor Custis), 1800s, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1234)
  - Lewis, Wm. M. Collection, 1800s, 110 card photographs (Box 27, Folder M1235)
    These photographs come from 110 individual and group pictures of various members of the Lewis family who lived in Hampton, NH; Gainesville, Ala.; and Columbus, Miss.; and of the allied families of Barry, Converse, Neilson and others. Some images have been colored; some contain original signatures.
  - Lewis, Wm. M. Collection, 1800s, 10 tintypes (Box 27, Folder M1235)
    These photographs come from 110 individual and group pictures of various members of the Lewis family who lived in Hampton, NH; Gainesville, AL; and Columbus, MS; and of the allied families of Barry, Converse, Neilson and others. Some images have been colored.
  - Lilly, E. J., E. J. Jr., and H. W., 1800s, card photograph (Box 27, Folder M1236)
  - Lincoln, A., 1860, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 42)
  - Lincoln, Abe, 1964-1970, Lloyd Ostendorf, artist, 4 black-and-white illustrations (Box 42)
    From the Lincoln Memorial University Collection.
  - Lincoln, Abraham (on his deathbed), 1865 Apr. 14, black-and-white photograph (Box 27, Folder M1239)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1860, Alexander Hesler, photographer, black-and-white photograph (Box 42)
    Includes descriptive note (photocopy).
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1862, 1866, 1898 and 1800s, 5 engravings (Box 27, Folder M1238)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1864 and 1800s, 1 black-and-white photograph and 1 card photograph (Box 27, Folder M1238)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1903, black-and-white photograph (Box 54)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1908, black-and-white etching (Oversize-folder 44)
    Etching by Max Rosenthal.
  - Lincoln, Benjamin, 1800s, black-and-white illustration (Box 54)
  - Lincoln, Benjamin, undated, 6 engravings (Box 27, Folder M1237)
  - Lincoln, Mary (Todd), undated, card photograph (Box 27, Folder M1240)
  - Little-Crow, a Sioux Chief, 1837, color lithograph (Box 59)
  - Livingston, Robert R. (1746-1813), 1862, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1241)
  - Livingstone, David, undated, 2 engravings and 1 clipping (Box 27, Folder M1242)
  - Locke, John, 1829 June 1, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1243)
  - Locke, John, undated, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1244)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1960, 1 black-and-white photograph and 1 lithograph (Box 27, Folder M1245)
  - Lokke, Carl Ludwig, 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 27, Folder M1246)
  - Long, Huey Pierce, circa 1925, engraving (Box 54)
    Includes a signed note.
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1910 and 1800s, 1 black-and-white illustration and 1 postcard (Box 27, Folder M1247)
    The illustration is a copy of a painting of Longfellow. The postcard is a copy of a painting of Longfellow's three daughters.
  - Longstreet, James, circa 1860s, 3 engravings (Box 27, Folder M1248)
  - Longstreet, James, Lieut. Gen., 1800s, lithograph (Box 42)
  - Longstreet, Maria Louise (Garland) and two of her children, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 27, Folder M1249)
  - Longstreet, Nicholas, undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 27, Folder M1250)
  - [Lorrain,] Claude, by W. Holl, 1800s, black-and-white engraving (Box 58, Folder M1798)
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1872 July 8 and 1800s, 1 card photograph and 1 engraving (Box 27, Folder M1252)
    Card photograph contains an original, dated signature.
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1934, black-and-white illustration (Box 27, Folder M1251)
  - Lowin, John, undated, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1253)
  - Loyola, Ignatius, undated, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1254)
  - Lucas, Ada M., 1902, black-and-white photograph (Box 27, Folder M1255)
  - Lucas, Daniel Bedinger, 1800s, engraving (Box 54)
  - Lucas, J. B. C., undated, engraving (Box 27, Folder M1256)
  - Lucas, James H. and his former residence, undated, 2 engravings (Box 27, Folder M1257)
  - Luce, Stephen Bleecker, 1901 July, black-and-white photograph (Box 27, Folder M1258)
  - Ludlow, Noah Miller, undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 27, Folder M1259)
  - Ludwig, Emil, 1900s, black-and-white illustration (Box 27, Folder M1260)
    Illustration is a copy of a photograph from the back of a book cover.